Profile

Senior Software Engineer with eight years' in the industry. As the first technical hire for an ambitious kiwi startup, I have spent the last two years designing, building and delivering a successful SAAS product to market. Prior experience in a much larger organisation provides excellent grounding as a technical manager and mentor, who has vast experience fixing urgent production issues.

Experience

Full Stack Developer (remote)

Wherewolf Ltd 2015 - Present

Wherewolf is a small startup based out of Queenstown, New Zealand, disrupting the adventure tourism industry. As their first technical hire, I report directly to the CTO and CEO.

Over the last two years I have designed and built Wherewolf's flagship SAAS product, which has been a huge success and allowed the company to gain momentum and grow rapidly across the adventure tourism industry.

The Wherewolf stack is Angular 4 / Typescript, Node.js and Postgres, running on Amazon EC2 / Amazon ECS (Docker).

- ~ Design and build Wherewolf Arrivals iPad App
- ~ Introduce docker for continuous deployment
- ~ Liaise with C level staff on product direction and priority
- ~ Develop API features
- ~ Carry out database performance analysis
- ~ Create dev tooling
- ~ Modernise business processes and SDLC
- ~ Troubleshoot legacy web apps
- ~ Maintain production environments
- ~ Perform code reviews
- ~ Mentor developers

Programming Teacher

Sydney Programming School (code4fun)

Sep 2016 - Mar 2017

Code4Fun are a commercial programming school in Sydney, Australia. As part of the teaching team I taught most afternoons and on occasional holiday camps.

Teaching classes and preparing courses provided a different take on patience and communication that I have since found useful professionally. Moreover, teaching to a student who has no grounding in a subject truly enforces your own knowledge of the fundamentals.

- ~ Teach programming to students aged 6-16 in groups of up to 22
- \sim Create and teach syllabi for Angular 2 (WhatsApp clone) and Python (Aboriginal Translation Portal)
- ~ Meet with parents to discuss student progress

Technical Lead (Payments and Gaming) OpenBet

Dec 2013 - Jan 2015

OpenBet are a London based trading platform providing software for most high street bookmakers in the UK, employing around 400 staff in 2015.

TLs at OpenBet handle the full management spectrum, from HR issues to performance appraisals. On the William Hill account, I was also responsible for managing the client's expectations on payments integrations and fixed odds gaming.

In 2015, the OpenBet stack was vanilla JS / HTML, a TCL application server, running on IBM Informix.

- ~ Manage a team of eight including two remote staff based in Athens
- ~ Make high level system architecture decisions
- \sim Run technical workshops with clients
- ~ Introduce docker for development and test environments
- ~ Monitor system-wide performance

- ~ Perform code reviews
- ~ Take interviews
- ~ Always available for escalation 24/7

Senior Problem Analyst (Tier III Support)

OpenBet Jun 2013 - Dec 2013

The time I spent with the support team serves me daily. I learned why best practices should be adhered to, why concise yet thorough processes are crucial, how to write effective documentation, how to find bugs quickly - and not cause them in the first place.

Most of all I gained the skills required to perform complex tasks quickly and under intense pressure.

- ~ Field urgent technical support escalations
- ~ Perform diligent triage of incoming issues
- ~ Analyse full stack performance
- ~ Increase the knowledge base documentation
- ~ Work shifts out of hours / overnight
- ~ Review fixes with the development teams
- ~ Be aware of SLAs and prioritise work accordingly
- ~ Liaise with clients often under difficult circumstances

Senior Developer

OpenBet Jan 2012 - Jun 2013

Developer

OpenBet Jun 2010 - Jan 2012

Education

Lancaster University

Computer Science BSc, First Class Honours

2007 - 2010

Head of department prize for best third year performance

Tech

Angular 4+	Typescript	Node.js
Docker	AWS Ecosystem (EC2 / ECS)	SQL, Postgres and Informix
Python	TCL	Bash
Unix	XCode	Cordova

Certificates IBM Programmer's Performance Workshop

2012 **IBM**

Informix training course lead by IBM focusing on performance analysis and optimisation (ZL1 840SW)

Award for excellence

Office Angels 2008

Whilst temping during the university summer (Office Angel of the Month!)

Open Source

clicker

clone-row

angular2signaturepad

An Ionic 3 / Angular 5 Seed Project

A Python utility to copy data between databases.

An Angular 4 signature pad component

www: http://lathonez.com | github: lathonez | twitter: lathonez | stackoverflow: lathonez